LUKE GRAHAM

San Diego, CA 92040

Phone: (909) 556-9869 | Email: luke.evan.graham@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/luke-graham-1865693 | Github: github.com/lukeevangraham

Portfolio: lukeevangraham.github.io

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in strategic storytelling as a Communications graduate, looking to design and develop user-focused web experiences. Experienced in React, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, Express, Handlebars, MySQL and Mongo. Strong interpersonal skills with six years of management experience and personal commitment to integrity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Node.js, MySQL, Mongo, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JSON, AJAX, Handlebars **Applications:** React, Firebase, GIT, Github, APIs, Postman, Express

PROJECTS

BookSearch | https://github.com/lukeevangraham/book-search | https://lgraham-book-search.herokuapp.com/

- Allows users to query the Google Books' API and save information to a separate database
- Lead developer
- MERN Stack, Bootswatch, Axios, HTML, CSS, GitHub, GIT, Bootstrap

BabyToday | https://github.com/lukeevangraham/Babay-Today | https://ayadav2-baby-logger.herokuapp.com/

- App to help parents log feeding, diaper and sleep events
- Developer in a group of four
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, jQuery, Express, Bootstrap

ClickyGame | https://github.com/lukeevangraham/clicky-game | https://lukeevangraham.github.io/clicky-game/

- Memory game utilizing React props
- Lead developer
- React, JavaScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

EXPERIENCE

Communications and Media Director Rancho Bernardo Community Church

2019 - Present

- San Diego, CA
- Produce a newsletter distributed to 550 readers and a two-minute video viewed by 800 people weekly
- Manage and develop organization website

Contemporary Worship Director

2012 - 2019

Rancho Bernardo Community Church

San Diego, CA

- Led a staff of four employees and 40 volunteers who executed 1,014 special events over six and a half years, the largest of which drew over 1000 people in consistent annual attendance
- Digitized music library, created multimedia experiences, implemented click track-synchronization between live band and video

Worship Director

2003 - 2011

LIFE Christian Fellowship

Chino, CA

- Developed and maintained website, audio/visual systems. Installed in-ear monitor system
- Promoted to a full-time position after first year of leading a team of 40 volunteers

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of California, San Diego, CA

An intensive six month long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS

Bachelor of Arts in Communication: California State University, Fullerton, CA